LAUGHING MAN FANSUBS
I'm a soldier - that means I'm
Both a defendant and the judge
I am standing on both ends of the flame
Rounding curves
Overtaking life and death,
I run and fight with false shadows
No matter how many threads of
deception are woven together,
The truth shall illuminate
the face of light
Save your tears for the day
When our pain is far behind
On your feet, come with me
We are soldiers stand or die
Save your fears, take your place
Save them for the judgement day
Fast and free, follow me
Time to make the sacrifice.
We rise or fall
Reporting from above the Kyushu Radio Tower.
A massive evacuation operation
conducted by the SDF began five days ago
with the discovery of an unexploded
shell at a subway construction site.
There was suspicion that the shell was a
tactical nuclear weapon from the Great War.
The SDF has finally succeeded in evacuating
the 35 million people living within
a 30 kilometre radius of the shell.
A select few experts speculate that this may
be another act of terrorism by the refugees.
With the media still having received
no explanation from the government,
Fukuoka has the feel of a city under martial law,
as part of the city sealed off by the SDF.
Abandoned
City
Inbound Routes Closed
Due to Bomb Disposal
Martial law, huh.
The government's response may not be ideal,
but it's not like all of its powers
were transferred to the military.
That's true.
Although we know Kuze's camouflaged
ship sank off the coast of Dejima,
we still can't say whether
any plutonium was on the ship.
It's also still uncertain whether the refugees
really triggered the massive blackout.
The populace continues to vent their anger
at the refugees against the government,
so the government continues to throw its support
behind any plans that will force the refugees' removal.
No one is pausing to think
about where this all leads.
Even if the Cabinet Intelligence Agency's
manipulation of information is the cause of this,
the rumours presently circulating
will not just disappear.
Batou, what's the matter with the Major?
I wrote in my report that she's been acting a bit strange
since she dove into Kuze's cyberbrain on Dejima, didn't I?
Right now, we have to focus on
dismantling the nuclear bomb.
The Cabinet Intelligence Agency
is already moving to control the
operation at the scene,
using media coverage control as an excuse.
I will negotiate with the Prime Minister
and see if she will give us the authority to
investigate the Cabinet Intelligence Agency.
When there's only circumstantial evidence?
The SDF is poised to invade. The Prime Minister
already has a major problem in Dejima, right?
At this point, I doubt she'd agree to something
that might become a national scandal.
If we screw this up.
Section 9 could get nailed again.
That's why I arranged it so that
you guys can intervene at the site.
You'd better find something there.
Hey, Major, why do you think
the refugees are still silent?
The truth has already silenced
itself before the phenomenon...
Kuze must've determined that.
For now, he's keeping his silence
and looking for a chance to
turn the tables again somewhere,
while keeping the truth
hidden, even from the refugees.
Why do you think that?
Because I would do the same, if I were him.
It seems your mind is elsewhere.
It's true that we're here because of you,
but it's not like we're so helpless
that we can't support you, you know.
Thank you.
I'm not entirely displeased with your sentiment.
Bomer, you and Pazu will participate in
the bomb disposal operation as planned.
Saitou, you come with me.
Hey, what's up with this?
Aren't we all going in?
I have an idea.
Besides, I have something I want you to do for me.
Has the Japanese Miracle been deployed?
Excuse me.
The deployment is already complete.
I see.
The results are unfortunate.
As soon as the bomb disposal
operation is complete,
I'll call a press conference
to announce the truth.
After that, the SDF will most
likely be able to invade Dejima.
Prime Minister, as I indicated in my report,
the possibility that the refugees
actually possess plutonium is minute.
It is most likely that the Cabinet Intelligence
Agency has caused this situation to come to pass.
I would like you to help me to temporarily
delay the SDF invasion of Dejima.
I read your report.
However, we're already out of time.
Based on our information from Russian authorities,
the government is poised to act on
the assumption that the plutonium
is already present in Dejima.
I don't mean to sound presumptuous,
but isn't that exactly what the
Cabinet Intelligence Agency wants?
No one wants it to happen,
but the end result of an SDF invasion
is a war with the refugees.
Please, reconsider using the
report in the Cabinet meeting.
If only I had seen this earlier...
Public Safety Section 9 was my last trump card.
Chief Aramaki, please remain
on alert for the time being.
Understood.
Reports from Squads 6 and 13.
They are in position on the top floor.
Understood.
We're Public Safety Section 9,
We're here at the Prime Minister's orders.
We haven't heard anything about that.
Don't worry about it.
It happens a lot out in the field.
Doesn't it?
The Prime Minister's signature, sir.
All right.
We just want our technicians on the front lines.
It can't be helped. Take them.
Understood.
So, what are you going to do?
I have business with that bureaucrat over there.
What is it?
We're on the verge of losing our
jobs, thanks to you,
but there are two or three things I have to ask.
Go right ahead.
Kyushu Radio
So that's it, huh.
We spent five days on the structural analysis.
We're finally about to begin
the disposal operation.
They're from Section 9,
if there's something you
can have them do, use them.
Right.
Kayabuki
"To Kayabuki with love"?
Talk about poor taste.
Similar messages were written on the
nosecones of Fatman, and also Scud missiles.
So they're copying America?
No idea. Couldn't say.
What are the Geiger counter readings?
They're positive.
But it doesn't seem as though they had the
technology or the time to build a nuclear warhead.
So it's just a plutonium bomb?
That's right.
But if it were to detonate,
the area within a 30 kilometre radius
would be contaminated with radiation.
We had no choice but to freeze it
while we evacuated the citizens
and deployed the Japanese Miracle.
There was no timer?
Fortunately, no.
I see.
But there are at least two detonation systems,
one linked to a vibration-based pressure sensor,
and another to a photo-conductor.
Wait, the inner lid also has something.
Are you really just Public Safety?
During the Great War, I was with the military.
Well, I was more of a specialist
in setting up bombs back then.
It's kind of appropriate to have
our talk up here, while a nuclear
warhead's being dismantled right below
us, don't you think?
So, how far do you intend to take this?
To take what?
How much worse are you going
to make the refugee situation?
You should ask the refugees or military analysts.
I'm not the expert.
Yeah, right.
Creating a medium who will give rise to mimics...
It's your old field of research.
This society already contains factors that make
it easy for situations like that to develop.
After all, human history has been shaped by those
with power, who have "programed" myths and legends.
In a world such as this,
a megalomaniac, whose desire to show off
became bloated without anyone noticing,
wanted to produce a hero bigger than himself,
Weren't the Individual Eleven a fake stand
alone complex created by a criminal like that?
Oh?
What an interesting story.
Hey, you fox.
But you're still second-rate.
Turn off the lights.
Isn't the lid loose?
Clear.
There it is.
One parallel reflective switch.
All right.
Inserting mirror,
I have cut all the photo-conductive material.
This model is an implosion-type nuclear bomb.
So it's their way of saying that
they chose not to make the bomb.
even though they had the time and technology,
What's going on?!
Another retrieval team just went through here.
What?
Bomer, what is your impression
of the bomb's structure?
It presents the whole "message from the refugees"
act, but there's something strange about it.
What?
The explosive is the M-112
that's used by the American army.
It's not the C-4 that the
refugees have been using.
I see.
You guys stay there until it's defused,
and then join the transfer unit.
But we still haven't found material evidence that
leads back to the Cabinet Intelligence Agency...
What you've found is enough for now.
Understood.
What do you mean, I'm second-rate?
We met a stand alone type hacker genius before.
I can't help but compare the
phenomenon he caused with this one.
When I compare him with the guys who killed themselves
here, they don't seem all that impressive anymore.
Then we investigated the
Individual Eleven's external memory
and discovered they were only mimics
who appeared because of the virus.
Oh?
They ended up acting as thought-guidance devices
that some criminal made, using the name of
the group who occupied the Chinese embassy.
The bastard who spread the virus probably
considers himself a damn good hacker, though.
Are you trying to imply that I'm
the one who created the virus?
I didn't say that.
Then what do you want me to talk about?
What do you think about the Individual Eleven?
Very well.
Supposing that the Individual Eleven
appeared because of a virus, like you said,
could you not say that they are as ingenious
as the stand alone type hacker, if not more so,
or even heroes,
for continually expanding the situation?
They did spread their thinking
with the mass-suicide performance.
But whose heroes did they become?
The Japanese citizens?
No way.
To the Individual Eleven
To the
Nameless Eleven
At best, they're clowns who gave the refugee
problem an opportunity to deteriorate.
To the Individual Eleven
To the
Nameless Eleven
Death!
To the Individual Eleven
In reality, their deaths
have already been forgotten.
To the
Nameless Eleven
To the Individual Eleven
I see.
But suppose the true purpose of the phenomenon
was to bring about the current situation
and not to keep these deaths in people's memories,
then could you not say that this criminal who produced
the Individual Eleven is the hacker genius?
Yeah, I can't deny that, unfortunately.
I'm still a bit skeptical when
you call him a genius, though.
The profile I can see from the Eleven's
thoughts and the virus's characteristics
is that of a particularist who
was possessed by the desire
to escape his sense of inferiority.
In the end, you can't impress people
if you're just forcing your own ideas onto them.
Unless there's something like a strong
belief, be it benevolent or malevolent,
you can't become a genius or a hero.
Belief...
That's right.
At least, that's what I believe.
And one more thing.
The one single factor that's absolutely necessary.
Luck: it would be indispensable.
Oh? Why is that?
It's obvious.
When it comes right down to it,
the existence of heroes and geniuses pretty
much depends on a third party's point of view.
To make a hero into a hero,
you first need the spectators response.
And that response can make or break a hero...
and that's all dependent on luck.
I see.
That is an interesting theory.
Still, I had no idea you
were this much of a talker.
Is that a compliment?
You can take it as one.
Then since I'm being complimented,
I'll mention one more thing:
the x-factor in this incident,
It's on the top floor.
Kuze Hideo was the only one among
the Eleven who didn't kill himself.
He then disappeared,
and by the time he reappeared,
he was the leader of the refugees.
What a strange story.
Is this a coincidence?
Or something that was set
up from the very beginning?
Since his behaviour was the total
opposite of the others in the Eleven,
it must be the x-factor you refer to.
But it can still be seen as something
that effectively contributes to the
movement towards the refugees removal.
While his actions are of a different sort,
the fact is that they are guiding the
situation towards a similar conclusion.
So, it seems the perpetrator masterfully
produced even the x-factor.
So that's how you'll put it?
Well, his actions could be said to be
speeding up the removal of the refugees.
The Nagasaki blackout lent further emphasis
to the camouflaged ship chase that
was streamed across the network.
And now, there's the nuclear
bomb right underneath us.
The government has no choice but to take the matter
seriously, now that Kuze has taken things this far.
However, was it really Kuze who did all this?
Isn't it actually some trumped-up act by
the perpetrator who is "producing" him?
Furthermore, couldn't you say that this
"producer" is aiding Kuze without realising it
and is starting to mimic Kuze's actions?
What do you mean?
Kuze returned to Dejima from Ostrov Iturup,
but he didn't have the plutonium on him.
Under normal circumstances,
he would've wanted to tell the refugees
and do damage control.
Yet a terrorist attack involving
plutonium has now occurred.
Then what?
Would he go along with the plans of his
"producer" and call the bluff, declaring war?
But he didn't do anything.
Right now, he's keeping quiet,
making the refugees stay quiet,
and waiting for a chance to turn the tables.
Or rather, isn't it actually Kuze who
gained a trump card by keeping quiet?
If Kuze, who was originally just an x-factor,
is actually the true genius... the true hero...
isn't it possible that the one
who thought he was producing Kuze
has somehow become Kuze's mimicker?
I'll leave the rest to you.
Roger.
They had faith in a fabricated
belief and even committed suicide.
yet they couldn't become anyone's heroes.
I wonder where their ghosts are wandering now.
Major, did the plutonium retrieval go well?
The operation is complete.
I see.
Using your external memory as a guide,
I tried to discuss Kuze in my own way,
but I wonder if it went as well as I hoped.
It did.
We'll go directly to Spring-8 from here.
The intelligence specialists obsession with realism
left evidence, and it will be their undoing.
if this plutonium matches what we found
in the Shinjuku nuclear power plant,
we will be able to prove that this was
the Cabinet Intelligence Agency's doing.
Understood.
Gouda.
Like Kuze, we haven't given up hope.
Is that right?
I forgot to ask you one thing.
I doubt there would be
another outbreak of the virus,
but we don't know the one remaining
factor that'll cause symptoms to appear.
We'd like to make a vaccine just in case.
If it were up to you,
what would you make the last factor?
If I were the one responsible,
I would find a host who was a
virgin before becoming a cyborg.
What?
It's an absolute necessity if you're
looking for a willingness to die
in order to become a hero for the people.
Of course, whether there would be people
with that rare quality was a wager,
You bastard...
There's a limit to how sick
of a bastard you can be.
Is that so?
Actually, I'm a virgin as well.
Our talk was delightful.
No, it was insightful.
I thank you for that.
My battle is not over yet, either.
Whether you people will stop me first,
or my goals will reach their conclusion
will depend on the x-factor.
Excuse me.
Finding out a galaxy
of planets and stars within me.
Listening to each of them
singing the same silent melody.
I've never seen such beauty
in possibility...
No smack of doubt or fear.
(Wake up)
I hear a voice.
(And show the light)
hear a voice calling out to me.
(Wake up)
I see inside
(the time is right)
see the light now ever holding me.
All the truth,
(All the truth)
All I need,
to make all this reality.
(it's inside)
The beauty within the shell.
(deep within the shell)
(within the shell)
(Wake up)
I hear a voice
(And show the light)
hear a voice calling out to me.
(Wake up)
(the time is now)
I see inside,
see the light now ever holding me.
All the truth,
(All the truth)
all I need,
to make all this reality,
it's inside
right here within the shell.